十九年前 我們開始相依爲命
19 years since we embarked on this life together.
六年前 你悄悄走到我房間裏説
Six since you tiptoed to my room and told me
有位先生給我取暖來了
there was a gentleman come to keep me warm.
我對蘇糖的專屬佔有權
Exclusive patronage of Sugar, by me.
過了這麼些年 你要離開我們啦
You're leaving us, then? After all these years?
這是什麼?
What is this?
這是你的
This is yours.
也是我的
And mine.
有位幸運的先生把傳説中的蘇糖買走了
Some lucky gent has taken the legendary Sugar off the market.
我們還沒享受到她的魅力呢
Before we'd had the benefit of her charms.
恐怕得説一切並不理想 你的子宮已經移位
I'm afraid all is not as it should be. Your womb has moved.
艾格尼絲流産過?
Agnes lost a child?
不 孩子生下來了      你們有小孩?
No, we have a child. We have?
是個女孩 索菲
A daughter. Sophie.
不舒服時 我就吃上兩片
On bad days I take a couple of these.
相信我 你會連自己都不認得的
Trust me, you will hardly know yourself.
我有個守護天使      我會回來找你的
I have a guardian angel. I will come back for you.
我多麼渴望能和你住在一起
I wish for all the world that I could live with you.
你們家族的男人腦子都有問題嗎?
What is the matter with the men in your family?
福克斯太太快死了
Mrs Fox is dying.
等不及想讓你也來了
I can't wait for you to join me.
我不能作爲家庭教師
Could I not, in fact,
和你住在一起嗎?
live with you as your new governess?
你不是認眞的吧?
You're not serious?
(本片含有部分性場面)
This programme contains scenes of a sexual nature.
-==破爛熊樂園傾情奉獻==- 本字幕僅供學習交流，嚴禁用於商業用途
紅玫瑰白玫瑰 第三集
-=破爛熊字幕組=-
翻譯：tpring LOVEKEICO
校對：tpring
時間軸：學生看不到馬老師 tpring
正體字幕轉製及校對：Uriel
又被他們耽擱了
Held up. As usual.
等等你 我胃口更好
Waiting for you has only ever sharpened my appetite.
又要梳理亨利的家産
Trying to sort out Henry's estate
還要處理那些雜事 唉
on top of everything else, it's just, ach!
所以我們之間的安排也行不通了
Which is why our current arrangement is no longer viable.
不能再在瑪麗勒本見面了
Marylebone must go.
可是威廉...      攤子太大 我管不過來了
But William... I am stretched too thin.
你不是總説...
How often have you said how...
我們的見面能讓你放鬆嗎?
restorative you find our time together?
沒錯 因此我想讓你搬到切普斯托路去
Indeed. Which is why I would like you to move to Chepstow Villas.
做索菲的家庭教師
And become Sophie's governess.
登堂入室
To live in your house?
和你住在一起?      你不是也想這樣嗎?
With you? I thought that was what you wanted?
你該不是改主意了吧      哦 威廉
Don't tell me you've changed your mind? Oh, William!
拉克曼太太
Mrs Rackham!
拉克曼先生?
Mr Rackham?
沒空 萊蒂 我忙着呢
Not now, Letty. I'm busy.
可是先生...
But sir...
克萊爾發現艾格尼絲在花園裏埋她的日記
Clara has found Agnes burying her diaries in the garden.
日記?      應該是想重新開始吧
Her diaries? Apparently she wants to make a fresh start.
科魯想把她關起來
Curlew wants to lock her up.
眞等不及要和你獨處了
I can't wait for you and I to be together.
契斯曼 幫蘇糖小姐拿行李
Cheeseman! Take Miss Sugar's bags.
我來吧
I'll take that.
腳下當心 小姐
Mind yer step, Miss.
萊蒂 這是...蘇糖小姐 新家庭教師
Letty, this is... Miss Sugar. Our new governess.
幸會 小姐
How do you do, Miss?
我希望...我相信她在這會很開心的
I hope... I trust she will be happy here.
這房子眞美
Such a beautiful house.
克萊弗女士上火車前會跟你談的
Miss Cleave will speak with you before she leaves for her train.
請跟我去你的房間
Allow me to show you to your room.
這是拉克曼太太的房間
Mrs Rackham's room.
還有我的
And my own.
房間沒有你原來的寬敞
The room is not as spacious as you're used to.
對
No.
不過能讓我們靠近一些就行了
But it will oblige us to remain very close together.
抱歉 先生      放那就行
Excuse me, Sir. Just come through with it.
克萊弗女士會給你講我女兒的情況
Miss Cleave will tell you all you need to know about my daughter.
毫無疑問 還有很多別的吩咐
And much more besides, I don't doubt.
拉克曼夫人也會來嗎?
And will Mrs Rackham be joining us?
我想不會的
I don't think so.
我本來打算心照不宣的
I had hoped this would go without saying,
可是你最好能看好索菲
but it would be best if you could take care of Sophie
讓拉克曼太太在日常活動中
in a manner that allows Mrs Rackham to go about her general business
見不到索菲
without actually seeing Sophie.
根本不見面?      正是
At all? Exactly.
那孩子讓她煩躁
She finds the child disturbing.
萊蒂 別放這裏 別放這裏 天啊
Letty! Not in here! Not in here! For heaven's sake!
和其他垃圾一起放更衣室去
Put it in the dressing room with all the other junk...
西班牙獵犬都要有眼色些
I swear a Spaniel takes better instructions.
別推 小心摔壞
No, don't push it! You'll break it.
這反應也太誇張了
This is a preposterous overreaction.
恕難苟同 我只是想埋葬過去
You will forgive me if I disagree. I merely wished to bury the past.
不能容許我無牽無掛地向前走嗎?
Am I not permitted to go forward unencumbered?
克萊弗女士?
Miss Cleave?
眞抱歉 我耽誤你了
Forgive me, I have kept you.
蘇糖小姐 我在這個家裏八年了
Miss Sugar. Eight years I have been in this house.
從孩子的奶媽當到保姆
In that time I have been both wet and dry nurse to this child.
老天      你會發現 索菲本質不壞
Heavens. You will find Sophie in the main a well-meaning thing.
她不笨 可她太容易分心
She isn't stupid but her mind is very easily jolted off the rails.
這種時候就需要嚴格要求
At such times a firm hand is required.
不要讓她走上...瘋狂之路
We don't want her going the way of a... a Bedlamite.
我會牢記的
I'll bear that in mind.
我們有兩套牀單互換
We alternate two sets of sheets.
她還尿牀呢 你知道嗎?
She wets the bed, you know?
牀單還沒乾 你得過會再來
The sheets are not yet dry, you'll have to come down later.
現在 該把你正式介紹給孩子了
Now, you must be formally introduced to the child.
克萊弗女士 我聽説你要趕火車
Miss Cleave, I believe you have a train to catch.
請讓我自己去見索菲吧
Please allow me to introduce myself to Sophie.
那你要當心 這孩子很會裝
Just watch out. She can be quite the little actress.
一不小心你就會被她耍的團團轉
She'll twist you round her little finger if you're not careful.
早安 索菲...
Good morning, Soph...
對不起
Forgive me.
你在睡覺
You were sleeping.
我是蘇糖小姐
I am Miss Sugar.
你好 小姐
How do you do, Miss?
我知道你叫索菲 你和你父親眞像
I know you are Sophie. You so closely resemble your father.
索菲 你還有別的房間嗎?
Sophie, do you have another room?
比如遊戲室?
A playroom, perhaps?
那你的玩具放哪裏呢?
So where do you keep your toys?
玩具你總該有吧?
You do have toys, don't you?
我有他
I have him.
他叫唐寧
His name's Twinings.
是我爺爺給我的
My grandpa gave him to me.
他本來騎着錫做的大象 裏面有茶葉
He was riding a tin elephant with tea inside,
可是那個被他們拿走了
but they took that away.
他這麼帥 不能老關在箱子裏啊
He's much too handsome to be shut up in that dusty chest.
克萊弗女士説
Miss Cleave says
臭烘烘的舊娃娃不能進我乾淨的房間
I'm not to have a smelly old doll in my good clean room.
她説她討厭這張黑臉
She says she doesn't like to look at his black face.
克萊弗女士已經走了
Well, Miss Cleave has gone now.
我想讓他和我們一起上課
I should like him to join us for our lessons.
現在我躺下睡覺 (兒童晚禱詞 1784)
Now I lay me down to sleep.
請主守護我的靈魂
I pray the Lord, my soul to keep.
如果我醒來之前死去
See me safely through the night
請主帶我靈魂同行 阿門
and wake me with the morning light. Amen.
怎麼了 有問題嗎?
What... What is it? What's wrong?
你像你父親嗎 小姐?      哦
Do you resemble your father, Miss? Oh...
這個問題有意思 索菲
That's a very good question, Sophie.
我倒沒想過
I've never thought about it.
還是你比較喜歡你媽媽?
Perhaps you favour your Mama?
一點都不喜歡 你喜歡你媽媽麼?
Not at all. Do you favour yours?
我也不知道 我生日之後就沒見過她了
I couldn't say. I haven't seen her since my birthday.
「親愛的日記 我已經被恐懼攫住」
'Dear diary, I am gripped by terror.
「他們叫來科魯醫生 他的黑包嚇壞了我」
'Dr Curlew has been called and his black bag frightens me.
「我求克拉拉別放他進來」
'I have begged Clara not to let him in
「可她説人人都在擔心孩子」
but she prattles that everyone is worried about the baby.
「已經夠遲了」
'How very late it is
「肯定快了什麼的」
'and that it must come soon.
「這是説誰的孩子?」
'Whose baby can this be?'
「眞希望威廉請人來家裏之前告訴我一聲」
I wish William would inform me about whom he invites to this house. '
至愛的
Dearest.
我正在想要不要去找你呢
I haven't known whether to come and find you.
不 不 最好別去
No, no, better not.
你過得怎樣?
How are you getting on?
後悔來這了 對吧?      一點也沒有
You rue the day you came, don't you? Not at all!
你看上去很疲憊
You have a weary look.
要不要我請個保姆幫你?
Would you like me to hire you a nursery maid?
不 不用 我確實沒睡覺
No, that's not necessary. It's true I haven't slept but,
不過那得怪牀
that's because of this bed.
太小了 我就知道
It's too small, I knew it.
威廉 它還沒被洗禮過呢
William, it hasn't been christened.
還記得我們的第一次嗎?
Do you remember our first time?
哦 我可夠丟人的
Oh! What a disgrace I was then.
可我看出你有很棒的潛質了
But I knew you were a great man in the making.
你照顧索菲眞的沒問題嗎?
Are you really managing all right with Sophie?
我們在一起很開心
We are very happy.
我想知道
I did wonder,
她生日是哪天?
when's her birthday?
八月...
August the...
某日 怎麼?
something. Why?
哦 索菲告訴我
Well, Sophie told me that
她從生日那天就沒見過艾格尼絲了
she hadn't seen Agnes since her birthday.
她是説她出生那天
She means since the day she was born.
早安 萊蒂
Good morning, Letty.
早安 索菲
Good morning, Sophie.
對不起 小姐 我是壞孩子
I'm sorry, Miss. I'm bad.
不 索菲 你不是壞孩子
No, Sophie, no, you're not bad.
一點都不是
Not at all.
快來擦擦乾淨吧
Let's get you clean.
我下面好痛
I'm sore down there.
那是你在濕牀單上睡太久了
Well, you've been sleeping in wet sheets for too long.
克萊弗女士有專門給你準備的藥膏嗎?
Did Miss Cleave have a special cream she used on you?
我去給你拿點吧
Well, I'll get you some.
我一直期盼着見你 福克斯太太
I cannot tell you how anxious I have been to see you, Mrs Fox.
她們説你近來的康復...
They say your recent recovery is...
完全是個奇蹟
nothing short of miraculous.
奇蹟舉世罕見 拉克曼太太
Miracles are rare, Mrs Rackham.
我還是相信我只是被調養痊癒了而已
I prefer to think I was simply nursed back to health.
得了吧
Come now!
亨利向我們保證他看到你就要死了
Henry assured us he had seen you on your deathbed!
對 亨利看到的是我最糟的時候
Henry saw me at my very worst, it's true.
我也很遺憾      你去的是健康修院
And I regret that. You've been to the Convent of Health...
對嗎?
.. haven't you?
不 是聖巴多羅買醫院
No. St Bartholomew's Hospital.
你是...眞的想告訴我
Are you... Are you seriously asking me to believe that
你被救出
you were snatched
那神祕惡魔的利齒 靠的只是調養好?
from the jaws of you-know-what by nothing more than good nursing?
你説的那家修院我從未耳聞
The convent of which you speak is not known to me.
若我捫心自問 福克斯太太
If I am scrupulously honest, Mrs Fox,
我也不知道它的確切位置
its precise location is a mystery to me.
幸好 他們給我派了位天使護身
Luckily, they have provided me with an angel escort,
時機成熟就會帶我去的
ready for when the time comes.
「我身下的擔架升起」
'The stretcher on which I lie is lifted
「經過灑滿陽光的林蔭 被擡向修院大門」
'and carried through the sunlit trees to the gates of the convent.
「我聽見來時的火車拉響汽笛
'I hear the train which delivered me hooting and
踏上歸程」
moving off on its return journey.
「將我護在羽翼下的天使 她就在門口守候」
'She whom has taken me under her wing is waiting at the gates.
「我被擡進修院
'I'm carried into the convent,
放在它中心的一間溫暖小房間」
into a warm cell at its very heart,
「彩繪玻璃窗之下 五光十色」
'which glows in colours from the stained-glass windows. '
相信我
Trust me.
早安 索菲
Morning, Sophie!
索菲 好姑娘
Sophie, good girl.
謝謝 小姐
Thank you, Miss.
今天要辛苦了 拉克曼太太?
Hard at work, today, Mrs Rackham?
是啊 克拉拉
Yes, indeed, Clara.
如果波德利和阿什韋
If Bodley and Ashwell,
威廉的笨蛋朋友可以出版
those idiot friends of William's, can publish books
他們那些生活隨感的書
that are no more than their opinions about life,
我爲什麼不能?
well, why can't I?
您在寫書?
You're writing a book?
就像寫日記 只不過是拿去出版的
It will be like my diary, but for the public.
好多同道中人都在翹首期盼
A great web of like-minded souls all waiting on
「艾格尼絲·皮戈特的
The Illuminated Thoughts and
眞知灼見與奇思妙想」呢
Preternatural Reflections of Agnes Piggott.
那纔是我的閨名 你知道嗎?
That's my real name, you know?
聽起來很有趣
It sounds fascinating.
要是我沒把舊日記都埋掉就好了
If only I hadn't buried all my old writings.
那可是多好的研究素材呀
They'd have been such invaluable research material.
哦 我相信它們的源泉還會靈感噴涌的
Oh, I'm sure there's plenty more where that came from.
對
Yes.
新書      我朝你父親要的
New books! I asked your father for them.
你舊的那些都過時了
Your old ones are out of date.
歷史在前進
History is on the move.
你每天都在變 你身邊的世界也在變
You change every day and so does everything around you.
連你也是?
Even you?
連我也是
Even me.
貓頭鷹和貓咪出海去玩兒
The owl and the pussycat went to sea
坐着豆綠色的船兒 (「貓頭鷹和貓咪」李爾 1871)
in a beautiful pea-green boat
他們帶了點蜂蜜 錢帶的不少
They had some honey and plenty of money
外邊包上一張五塊錢的鈔票
wrapped up in a five-pound note
貓頭鷹看一眼天上的月亮
The owl looked up at the stars above and
彈着小吉他輕輕的歌唱...
sang to his small guitar...
你晚上冷嗎? 天轉涼了
Are you cold at night, now the weather's turned?
要不要加塊毯子?      好的 謝謝
Would you like another blanket? Yes, please.
你怎麼知道?
How did you know?
你小時候 保姆也會給你加塊毯子嗎?
Did your nurse bring you an extra blanket when you were a little girl?
不會 所以我纔知道你想要一塊
No. But that's how I know you'd like one.
看 有條蟲子在拱
Look, there's a wiggly worm!
威廉 我們誰都聊到了 就是沒聊你
William, we have discussed everyone except you.
你的生活越來越神祕了 我眞好奇
Your life is becoming quite shrouded in mystery and I am so curious.
比如説 你給女兒找到家庭教師沒有?
Did you, for example, ever find a governess for your daughter?
找到了 謝謝
Yes, I did, thank you.
該不是被挽救的失足少女吧?
Not a rescue girl, I hope?
爲什麼這麼想?
What makes you think that?
福克斯太太在努力説服每個
Well, Mrs Fox is striving to convince anyone with the least
缺僕人的人接納她的改造成果
servant problem to take one of her reformed specimens.
她可不敢再找我了
She knows better than to approach me.
我收了一個在廚房裏
I had a rescue girl in my kitchen,
馬上就得開除了
was obliged to dismiss her very swiftly.
怎麼 出了什麼事?
Why? What happened?
體面人面前不好啓齒
Nothing I could discuss in polite company.
我算體面人嗎?
Am I polite company?
哦 威廉 你可是自成一派
Oh, William. You are sui generis!
我覺得和你什麼都能談
I feel as if I could discuss any subject with you.
它就是這樣 我説吧      蘇糖小姐 我又找到一個
Yes, he is, isn't he? Miss Sugar, I found another one.
蘇糖小姐 你好嗎?
Miss Sugar, how do you do?
我很好 謝謝 先生
Very well, thank you, Sir.
今天天氣不錯
A brighter day today.
對 對 所以我帶索菲到戸外上課
Yes, yes, it is. I brought Sophie outside for her lesson.
她太蒼白了      淑女越蒼白越好
She's grown so pale. A lady can never be too pale.
可孩子需要新鮮空氣
But a child needs some air.
我發現索菲眞是個努力的孩子
I find Sophie such a hardworking little girl.
那你太幸運了
How very agreeable for you.
很好 索菲
Very good, Sophie.
蘇糖小姐
Miss Sugar.
拉克曼先生 一會如果您有空
Mr Rackham? Might I have a word with you later,
我能否跟您談談?
when you have a moment?
當然可以
Of course.
那位女士是誰 索菲?
Who is that lady, Sophie?
我不知道 小姐 可我見過她
I don't know, Miss. I've seen her before.
我父親誇我是個好孩子 小姐
My father says I was a good girl, Miss.
他不是那麼説的
That's not what he said.
你想見我
You wanted to see me?
對
Yes!
我想你了
I miss you.
今天看見你在花園裏
To see you in the garden today
卻不能碰你 眞是痛苦
and not be able to touch you was torture.
眞的?
Really?
我太邋遢了
I feel so dowdy.
我的好衣服都在箱子裏呢
All my good clothes are in the trunk.
照顧蘇菲不需要你原來的行頭
You don't need your old get-ups to take care of Sophie.
嗯 那倒是
No, of course not.
可我不想你對我膩味      膩味?
But I don't want you to grow bored of me. Bored?
蘇糖 你拯救了我
Sugar, you saved me!
你不知道我在這房子裏感覺多陌生
You can't imagine how much of a stranger I felt in this house.
可是你來了...
But then you arrived and...
這是我們的家了
We have a home here.
正是
Exactly that.
我很感激
And I am grateful.
多感激?      感激不盡
How grateful? Very grateful.
不過我得走了
But I must go now.
波德利和阿什韋要發佈新書了
Bodley and Ashwell are launching their new book.
「社會至惡」
The Great Social Evil.
忙完了再來?
Perhaps later?
看吧
We'll see.
是誰?      蘇糖小姐 對不起
Who's there? Miss Sugar, I'm sorry!
我...我在找拉克曼太太
I just, I need to check for Mrs Rackham.
簡妮? 克拉拉?
Janey? Clara?
艾格尼絲 你在哪?
Agnes, where are you?
艾格尼絲?
Agnes?
艾格尼絲 你在哪?
Agnes, where are you?
拉克曼太太
Mrs Rackham?
我的天使
My angel!
我就知道你會來的
I knew you'd come!
艾格尼絲 你幹什麼了?
Agnes, what have you done?
求你 我準備好了
Please, I'm ready.
救我走      我...我不能
Get me away! I... I can't.
你是我唯一希望了
You're my only hope.
我會救你的
I will help you.
什麼時候      快了
When? Soon.
你保證 你保證?
You promise? You promise?!
對 可是首先我得告訴他們你很安全
Yes. But first I have to let them know you're safe.
安全?
Safe?
在這所房子裏 和他在一起?
In this house? With him?
別怕 艾格尼絲
Don't worry, Agnes.
我在守望着你
I'm watching you.
我能看見一切
I see everything.
別動
Stay still.
拉克曼先生
Mr Rackham!
我跟你説了幾個月了
I've been telling you for months,
你妻子需要離開這裏 由專家治療
your wife requires specialist treatment away from this house.
我就是要求你讓她快點痊癒
I am asking you to help hasten her recovery,
就在這裏 她自己家裏
here, in her own home.
沒人會指責丈夫因爲妻子摔斷腿
Nobody blames a man for sending his wife to hospital
或染上天花就把她送進醫院
if she has a broken leg or contracts smallpox!
這有什麼可比性
That is a facetious comparison.
哦 拉克曼 別再自欺欺人
Oh, Rackham. You simply have to rid yourself of this notion
以爲你妻子很健康
that your wife is a well person
只是偶爾犯病
who suffers occasional bouts of illness.
她已經重病纏身 只是偶爾會好一天
She is a very sick person who occasionally has a good day.
她最近狀態非常好...
She's been doing marvellously well these...
好什麼好
Of course she hasn't!
這可笑的鬧劇該收場了
Now, this absurd pantomime has gone too far.
艾格尼絲是時候承認她是個母親了
It's high time Agnes admitted to being a mother.
我對她無計可施了
She has me at my wits' end.
我中了什麼邪要叫科魯來啊
And why the hell did I ever call Curlew?!
好了 親愛的        他想把我妻子關進地獄
Hush, my love. He wants me to condemn my wife to a living hell
就因爲她不會埋東西
because she can't use a spade.
威廉 你冷靜點
William, you're beside yourself.
今後她倒是不會找麻煩了
She'll be no trouble from now on, though. Oh, no.
科魯總算有用了一回
Curlew has finally made himself useful in that respect.
什麼意思?      要給她用鎭靜藥了
What do you mean? She's to be sedated.
整日整夜
Day and night.
這至於嗎?      我剛纔怎麼跟你説的?
Is that necessary? What have I just been telling you?!
整日整夜
Day and night.
你明白嗎?
Do you understand?!
我的天使
My angel.
傑西·夏普樂頓剛從桑吉巴回來
Jessie Sharpleton, just back from Zanzibar,
還有克勞倫斯·弗里
and Clarence Ferry.
噢 他是「她之墮落」的作者
Ah, he wrote Her Regrettable Lapse.
我在赫馬基特見過這本書
I saw it at the Haymarket.
我多麼喜愛和這些新時代的同行相聚
How I love to be surrounded by my denizens of the age to come.
我説 拉克曼      沃森勳爵
I say, Rackham. Lord Watson.
你小子夠忙的
You've been a busy chap.
我在威尼斯的藥鋪裏都能看見你的臉
Even in the apothecaries in Venice I find your phiz,
瓶瓶罐罐上全印着
stamped on all the little pots and bottles.
摩登時代的奇蹟 先生
A miracle of the modern age, sir.
我身在倫敦 就可以在巴黎
I can be making a fool of myself in Venice and
和威尼斯傻名遠揚
Paris without ever leaving London!
説的好
Very good!
克拉拉 拉克曼太太能坐起來眞是少見
Clara, I am surprised to see Mrs Rackham sitting up.
我的疼痛減輕了 所以克拉拉減少了藥的劑量
Clara has decreased my medication now that I am in less pain.
這不是克拉拉能決定的
That is not a decision for Clara.
是我吩咐的
She was doing as I asked.
我遭受了最大的羞辱
I have suffered a most humiliating rebuff.
馬車伕説他被禁止載我去教堂
Cheeseman says he's forbidden to take me to church.
親愛的 今天是星期五
My dear. It's Friday.
我的教堂
My church.
我需要奇蹟的治癒 威廉
I need a miracle of healing, William.
可是艾格尼絲 你不能走動
But Agnes... Agnes, you cannot walk.
馬伕可以背着我     別
Cheeseman can carry me. No.
我不想讓你成爲笑柄
I will not have you become a laughing stock.
你到底有多怯懦 多死板 威廉
What a cowardly, conventional man you are, William.
艾格尼絲 你生病了
Agnes, you are ill.
我是爲了照顧你
I'm trying to take care of you.
你什麼時候照顧了我?
When have you ever taken care of me?
什麼時候?!
When? When?!
艾格尼斯 別
Agnes, no!
別 艾格尼斯...
No, Agnes...
別在僕人面前這樣!
Agnes, not in front of the servant!
艾格尼絲 停下
Agnes! Stop it!
艾格尼絲
Agnes!
我的身體快變成行屍走肉了
My body is turning into raw meat and
而你卻只在乎別人怎麼想
all you care about is what other people think!
艾格尼絲 看在上帝份上!     拉克曼太太 求你了!
Agnes, for pity's sake! Mrs Rackham, please!
停下來 停下來!
Stop it, stop it!
你弄痛我了
You're hurting me.
找別人玩吧
Go play with someone else.
(親愛的科魯醫生 您最近...)
dear dr. curlew, how...
索菲
Sophie.
看到你下樓眞好
How nice it is to see you downstairs.
你的媽媽在哪 小姐?
Where is your mama, Miss?
她在家 自己的房子裏
She's at home, in her house.
一個人嗎?     不
All alone? No.
有人會來看她
She has visitors.
下一張卡是爲她做的
The next card I make is for her.
很期待 索菲
We'll see, Sophie.
上個聖誕節 你在照顧誰?
Who were you looking after last Christmas?
一個小男孩 克里斯托弗
A little boy, Christopher.
現在誰照顧他?
Who's looking after him now?
不知道
I don't know.
總可以再給他做張卡吧?
Surely we should make him a card?
聖誕快樂 所有人
Merry Christmas, one and all!
艾格尼絲呢?
Where's Agnes?
樓上 睡着呢
Upstairs, sleeping.
噢 用鎭定劑了吧 這樣最好
Ah, doped up. Better for everybody.
這我不好説
I don't know about that,
可是索菲可以第一次加入我們了
but it does mean that Sophie can join us for the first time.
看看孩子都長這麼大了!
Will you look at the size of the child!
哈哈!
Ha-ha!
現在告訴我 禮物在哪裏?
Now, then, where are the presents?
謝謝 索菲小姐
Oh, thank you, Miss Sophie.
謝謝
Thank you.
謝謝你 索菲小姐
Thank you, Miss Sophie.
蘇糖小姐     別 索菲...
Oh, Miss Sugar. No, no. Er, Sophie...
請讓我來
Please, allow me.
拉克曼先生 你眞是善良仁厚
Erm, Mr Rackham, that's very generous.
是書嗎 小姐?     是的 索菲
Books, Miss? Yes, Sophie.
莎士比亞
Shakespeare.
你父親和我的共同愛好
Your father and I share a passion.
索菲小姐
Miss Sophie.
這個珍貴的儀器來自於我
This is a precision instrument entrusted to me
曾經遇到的一位探險家
by an explorer I once met.
讓我來告訴你它的用法
Let me show you how it works.
你把這個取下來 從這邊看過去
You take this off, look through the window.
讓我來 索菲
Allow me, Sophie.
嘴張開!
Open up!
小姐?     嗯?
Miss? Hmm?
我長大後 能當探險家嗎?
Do you think I could be an explorer when I'm older?
爲什麼不能呢
I don't see why not.
也許這不合規矩 女性探險家
It mightn't be permitted, a lady explorer.
現在是摩登時代了 索菲
These are modern times, Sophie.
女人現在什麼都能做
Women can do all sorts of things nowadays.
也許我能去那些 男士探險家們
Perhaps I could explore the places the gentlemen explorers
不想去的地方
just don't wish to explore.
也許你可以的
Perhaps you could.
現在叫醒媽媽也沒用了
There's no use anyone waking my mama now,
是嗎 小姐?
is there, Miss?
她錯過了一切
She has missed everything.
她病的很嚴重 索菲
She is very ill, Sophie.
我想她很快會死掉 然後被他們埋進土裏
I think she'll die soon and they'll put her in the ground.
如果你願意的話
If you like,
我們可以一起讀讀明天要給你的書
we can read the book I gave you tomorrow.
好的 我願意
Yes. Yes, I'd like that.
晚安 蘇糖小姐
Goodnight, Miss Sugar.
上帝保佑你      你也是 索菲
And God bless. You too, Sophie.
克里斯托弗?
Christopher?
「科魯向我彎下腰」
"Dr Curlew leans over me.
「沒人能阻止他的行爲」
There is no-one to stop him having his way.
「他把雙手放在我的腹部 我體內的惡魔」
"He places his hands on my belly and the demon inside me
「暴怒起來 左衝右突 想要撕裂我逃出來」
"lunges in rage and terror and then tears its way out of me.
「星星在我眼中炸開」
"Stars burst behind my eyes.
「一瞬間 我瞥見這骯髒的生物」
"I glimpse the vile creature only for an instant.
「一絲不掛 黏黏的 滿身是血」
"Naked, made of blood and slime. "
很快你就會到對你更好的地方 親愛的
Soon you'll be in a place where you'll get better, my love.
你也想好好的 對吧 艾格尼絲?
You do want to be good, don't you, Agnes?
「行善吧 好姑娘」(查爾斯·金斯利)
Be good, sweet maid.
熱...
Hot...
你覺得熱
Are you hot?
第一次的晚上我不是故意弄疼你的
I didn't mean to hurt you that first night.
我是太着急了 忘乎所以
I was made hasty by urgency.
我以爲...
And I thought...
我以爲開始了你就會感到愉悅的
I thought once we were under way you would enjoy it.
「六個壯漢 把我擡起」
# Six strong men, lift me up
「噢 別讓我掉下去」
# Oh, no, don't let me fall... #
已經過了很久了
It's just been such a long time.
別害怕 親愛的
Don't be afraid, dear heart.
讓我來擁抱你
I'm going to embrace you.
如果疼了就告訴我 好嗎?
You'll let me know if I hurt you, won't you?
我絶對不會傷害你
I wouldn't hurt you for the world.
「他們紮了我的手 我的腳」
# They've pierced my hands and feet.
「把我的骨頭都數過」(《聖經舊約·詩篇》22)
# They've numbered all my bones. #
救我!
Help me!
救我
Help me.
請救救我
Help me, please.
艾格尼絲
Agnes.
他們給我毒藥 傷害我
They give me poison and they hurt me.
他傷害我
He hurts me,
他的醫生也一樣
and his doctor does the same.
在我同一個地方
In the same place, always.
那個醫生傷害你?
The doctor hurts you?
他刺進我體內
He pushes inside.
用他的尖鋭的喙挖我鑿我
He digs away at me with his sharp beak.
艾格尼絲 沒人會再傷害你了
Agnes, no-one is going to hurt you any more.
他們想殺掉我
They're going to kill me.
蟲子吞噬了我的日記
Worms have eaten my diaries.
沒人會知道我存在過
No-one will know I existed!
艾格尼絲 你的日記在我這裏很安全
Agnes, your diaries are safe with me.
過來 我帶你回牀上
Come on, let's get you to bed.
幾點了?     七點了 小姐 拉克曼先生在找你了
What time is it? Seven, Miss. And Mr Rackham's asking for you.
「我們肉體所承受的苦難終將結束」
"But our suffering in the flesh will some day end.
「在睡夢中我已經穿越 看到了」
"I have myself travelled in my sleep to see the place
「我們將被渡入第二軀體的地方」
where we will pass into our second body,
「天堂裏的天使們保護着我們」
"kept safe for us by the angels of paradise. "
我在艾格尼絲房間裏找到的
I found it in Agnes' room.
看起來她在寫小説
It seems she's writing a novel.
她故事講得不錯 不是嗎?
She tells a good story, doesn't she?
你在開玩笑嗎?
Are you making a joke?
當然不是...     這是發瘋!
No, of course not... It is madness!
整個精神錯亂
It's complete lunacy.
好吧 這只是她的一種慰籍...
Well, she's just consoling...
別説了!
Stop it!
艾格尼絲還是得送走
Agnes is to be put away.
去精神病院 明天就走
In an asylum. She leaves tomorrow.
科魯會監督她的治療     可是威廉
Curlew will supervise her treatment. But William...
她會被悉心照料的
She will be meticulously cared for.
我意已決
The decision has been made.
好吧 那這樣説的話
Well, in that case,
好像不需要叫我來
I can't think what you need to know from me.
我需要知道自己不是禽獸!
I need to know I'm not a monster!
願上帝原諒我 蘇糖
God forgive me, Sugar
他們來的時候 我呆在這會受不了
I can't bear to be here when they come.
我會去俱樂部
I'll stay at my club.
如果艾格尼絲反抗呢?
What if Agnes should resist?
她會先被麻醉
She will be sedated.
科魯先生找了四個壯漢一起來
And Curlew will have four strong men with him.
四個?     確保一切顯得體面些
Four? To ensure that it proceeds with dignity.
艾格尼絲會被治好的
Agnes will be cured.
科魯保證了
Curlew swears it.
她會回到家
She will come home
我們讓她見到索菲
and we shall introduce her to Sophie.
最後成爲眞正的媽媽
She'll be a mother at last.
整棟房子的人死絶了嗎?
Damn it, is the entire house asleep?!
再來杯威士忌嗎 先生?     是的
Another whisky, sir? Yes.
哦 天啊 天啊
'Oh, deary, deary.
可憐的寳貝
'You poor baby. '
別!
No!
你需要一個溫軟的牀舖
'You need a nice, soft bed
好好躺下
'to lie down in. '
不要 離我遠一點
No. No. Get away from me.
你不是説眞的吧
You don't mean that.
讓我一個人呆着!
Leave me alone! Leave me alone.
親愛的?
Oh, deary?
艾格尼絲 醒醒
Agnes. Agnes, wake up.
喝了它
Drink this.
全喝完
Drink it all up.
我會回來 別睡過去
I'll be back. Don't go back to sleep.
時候到了?
Is it time?
照我説的做 艾格尼絲
'Do exactly as I say, Agnes.
我會守望着你 別擔心
'I'll be watching you. Don't worry.
目的地會顯現在你面前
'The right destination will reveal itself to you.
你所選即是目的地
'The place you choose will be the right place
因爲是你選擇了它
because you chose it. '
洛斯特威西爾 (康沃爾郡 英國西南)
Lostwithiel
蘇糖小姐?
Miss Sugar?
我眞的不知道她去了哪裏
I really have no idea where she could have gone.
我眞的很難相信 拉克曼太太
I find it very hard to believe that Mrs Rackham
能夠逃出這裏
could have made her way out into the world
不是有人幫她
without the help of someone.
女人可以做出很多不可思議的事
It is remarkable what a woman can do
如果用盡她全副心智的話
when she sets her mind to it.
她根本沒有全副心智
What's left of her mind.
這對拉克曼先生一定是很嚴重的打擊
This will be such a blow for Mr Rackham.
希望拉克曼太太會在他之前回來
I do hope Mrs Rackham returns before he does.
是啊
Indeed.
拉克曼太太身體極度虛弱
Mrs Rackham is an extremely vulnerable individual.
如果有人幫助過她...
And if someone has helped her...
這就等同於謀殺
.. well, that's tantamount to murder.
當你到達目的地
'When you arrive at your destination,
走進郷邨裏
'walk deep into the countryside.
問修院的路怎麼走
'Ask to be shown to the convent.
永不放棄
'Don't take no for an answer.
答應我
'Promise. '
第三集 終
謝謝觀賞